Rakesh Kumar Choudhary

Senior Software Engineer
At MPS Limited

+91-9999238493

rakeshkrc.nav@gmail.com

Career Objective

7 Years of experience in different domains of the IT industry such as Banking, Media, Education, Entertainment and E-commerce. Skilled in all phases of the software development life cycle. Expert in translating business requirements into technical solutions and fanatical about quality, usability, security and scalability.

Technical Expertise

- Strong expertise on PHP in a LAMP architecture, Open Source CMS (Drupal), MySQL,
 Codelgniter, Laravel and Zend Framework.
- Experience in common third-party APIs Coding & Troubleshooting
- Experience in customization & integration of Open Source Applications and Payment Gateway integration
- Proficiency in Enhancement of existing website and to Optimize pre-written PHP code & MySQL queries
- Good knowledge of relational databases, version control tools
- Maintain and Update Existing Websites & Works on Multiple Projects Simultaneously
- Proven track record in problem solving and debugging in the LIVE Environment

Management Expertise

- Involved in Milestone Preparation & tracking of its progress and Helping team member to achieve their milestone, if required
- Involved in project planning, designing, prototyping and successful execution that meets all functional specifications on time
- Supports & Coordinates the team members of Design & Development when needed
- Daily Progress Reports & Meeting with PM regarding milestone, major technical issues etc
- Resolve technical issues that are escalated by junior and mid-level developers
- Work closely with the TL/PM of Design, Testing & Optimisation department to assist in the analysis, evaluation and recommendation of application, technology & requirement.

Work Experience

- Working as Senior Software Engineer at MPS Limited from 20-June 2019 to till date
- Working as Senior Software Engineer at UXD Media Pvt. Ltd. from 3-April 2018 to 15-May 2019.
- Working as Software Engineer at Apptology Technology Pvt. Ltd. from 27-June 2016 to 2-April 2018.
- Working as Software Engineer at Poonam Advertisers & Printers Pvt. Ltd. from 14-June 2014 to 25-June 2016.
- Working as Software Engineer at Giga Soft System Pvt. Ltd. from 7-Feb 2014 to 13-June 2014.

Education Qualification

MCA From TMBU Bhagalpur in 2010.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages	PHP
PHP Framework	Codelgniter, Laravel, Zend
CMS	Drupal
Web technology	HTML, Java Script, Ajax, Jquery, Angular JS
Database	MySQL

Project	Mag+ Now					
Project Description	In the CMS admin tool, users will have the option to Create New					
	Issue along with browse already published issues.					
Date	11 September 2020, Present					
Role	Senior Software Engineer					
Technology	Drupal 9					
Responsibilities	 Drupal programming and theming Worked on Admin Panel & CMS Management Troubleshooting & resolution of issues like optimisation, technical, performance & security in the website Worked on Alternatives, Specifications, Price Alert set, In stock alert set & Launch Alert Set Worked on Deals, Coupons & Users Module Implement Jquery, AJAX, Javascript, JSON 					

Project	TGL THERAPEUTIC GUIDELINES					
	https://tglpubadmang.mpstechnologies.com/					
Project Description	It is Australian project to manage the Medicine related information.					
Date	15 July 2019, 10 September 2020.					
Role	Senior Software Engineer					
Technology	Laravel, MySQL, Angular					
Responsibilities	 Worked on Admin Panel Management 					
	 Worked on Products, Coupons & Users Module 					
	Implement Jquery, AJAX, Javascript, JSON					

Project	UXD Media			
Project Description	CMS Based Ecommerce small project https://zamazing.co.za https://www.bookspadho.com/ http://www.jap-express.com/			
Date	3-April 2018 to 15-May 2019.			
Role	Senior Software Engineer			
Technology	Codeigniter, MySQL			

Responsibilities	 Worked on Admin Panel Management Worked on Products, Coupons & Users Module Implement Jquery, AJAX, Javascript, JSON

Project	Click Ipr on Client side.	
Project Description	http://ourworld.goingtoschool.com/	
Date	27-Jun-2016 To 2-April-2018	
Role	Software Engineer	
Technology	Codeigniter, MySQL	
Responsibilities	Admin Panel of HR Management	

STRENGTHS

- Extensive and demonstrable experience in web development
- Excellent team-working, rapport-building skills and able to work unsupervised and deliver quality results fast
- Proven communication skills in English & Hindi
- Motivated, flexible and dynamic self-starter, Willingness to regularly expand and refresh technical skill set using online/self-training
- Proven ability to carry out project work from start to finish & multiple tasks to different deadlines
- Experience of website development for a medium to large-sized company & also worked in an international project
- Experience working in an organization in the business of Consulting, Technology, Outsourcing, Professional Services
- Ability to identify, develop and implement new technologies through self-exploration

Personal Details

Father Name	Prabhaker Choudhary
Mother Name	Sunita Devi
Date of Birth	01-03-1981
Language Known	English, Hindi.
Nationality	Indian
Interest	Listening to music
Correspondence Address	F 25 Jawaharpark New Delhi 110062
WhatsApp	+91-7678306531

I hereby of	declare	that the	above	written	particulars	are	true to	the b	est of	f my	knowle	edge
and belief	•											

Date :	
Place :	(Rakesh Kumar Choudhary)